Medical appointments would be scheduled during business hours, and I knew that I would need time off to recover from surgical procedures. Again, being a typical lawyer, I had done my due diligence on what to expect from treatment. Admittedly, a lot of that was through Doctor Google, perhaps not my best move and I wouldn't recommend that. (Laughter) But while I was ready for all the physical side effects, what really scared me was this thing called chemo brain. Chemo brain presents itself through memory loss, an inability to concentrate and an inability to solve problems. And if this happened to me, I wondered how I was going to do my job as a lawyer. Would I be forced to leave work? And how could I possibly have a discussion with my manager about reasonable adjustments to my working arrangements when I didn't know how I was going to be impacted? I was fortunate to have a supportive manager who was happy to see how things went as we went along, rather than requiring a concrete plan up front. I was lucky that while he may not have even known about this concept of reasonable adjustments, to him, it was just common sense. But I've learned that it's not common sense to everyone. Everyone going through treatment will learn how it impacts them and what their limitations are. And they'll learn to adjust for that. So for me, there were the tips and tricks that I learned about the treatment itself, like, before you go to chemo, you need to make sure you're really well hydrated and that you're warm, because it helps the nurses to find your veins. And make sure that you don't eat any of your favorite food, either before or after chemo, because you're going to be throwing that up and you won't ever want to look at it again. (Laughter) I learned that one the hard way. And then there were the tricks for managing my workflow. I scheduled chemo for first thing on a Monday morning. I knew that from the time I left the cancer care unit, I had about four hours before this fog screen would come down and I would start to be sick. So I would use that time to clean my inbox and make any urgent calls. The worst of the sickness would be gone within about 48 hours. And then I would log back into work from home. This treatment continued and I knew what to expect. I was able to set reasonable expectations with my business partners about what I could do and the time frames that I could do it in. But I still remember the hesitation in their voices when it came to asking for things. And asking me to do things by a certain time. And trust me, these were people that were not afraid of setting a good deadline. (Laughter) I got the impression they didn't want to put any extra pressure on me while I was going through treatment. And while I appreciated the sentiment, I actually needed the deadlines. To me, that was something within my control and something that could stay in my control when there were so many things that couldn't. And as I was working from home, I was thinking about how employers should be applying this concept of reasonable adjustments in our current age, where one in two Australian men and women will be diagnosed with cancer by the age of 85. So, as we continue to work longer and longer into older age, the chances of having a serious illness while we're in the workforce are increasing. And with technology enabling us to work anywhere, any time, reasonable adjustments are no longer contingent upon whether or not you can continue to physically make it into the physical office. Reasonable adjustments are also not about just offering a longer break or a comfier chair to sit in, although those things might be good, too. At the very least, we need to be applying the flexibility policies and strategies we've developed for other scenarios, like for people with family responsibilities. But how can we ensure that people are even having a conversation about what reasonable adjustments might look like for them if a manager's first response is to say, "Oh no, don't come back to work until you're better." And a light went on for me. It must be compulsory for managers to have to have these conversations with their employees. And lessons from people like me, that have really benefited from working through treatment, need to be more widely shared. And I thought about what could be done to guide these conversations, and then an amazing colleague of mine, Camilla Gunn, developed a "Working with Cancer" toolkit. The toolkit provides a framework for those diagnosed, their managers, their carers and their coworkers to have conversations about cancer and the work support available. Camilla and I have now been to other organizations to talk about the toolkit and how it can help to guide through what, quite frankly, are otherwise some pretty awkward conversations. And I'm pleased to say that the uptake of the toolkit is increasing. So what should be a manager's first response when somebody says that they're sick and they don't know how it's going to impact their work? It must be this: "To the extent that you are able, and want to, we would love to work out an arrangement for you to continue to work through treatment." We need to start positively engaging people with serious illness to keep them in the workforce, rather than paternalistically pushing them away. I've told you my story because I want you to know the benefits that working through treatment brought me. And I also want to change your perceptions if you think that somebody going through treatment is just bored, frail and vomiting a lot. And yes, these things were true some of the time, if not a lot of the time, but I was also determined to push myself at work as much as I had always done. And I was able to do that because my employer gave me the choice. Most importantly, I'm telling you because while it's a seemingly obvious choice to give someone, it's not one that is always offered or encouraged. And it must be. Thank you. (Applause)
Tendría citas médicas durante mis horas de trabajo, y sabía que necesitaría tiempo libre para recuperarme de los procedimientos quirúrgicos. De nuevo, como abogada típica, hice las debidas diligencias sobre qué esperar del tratamiento. Lo admito, gran parte fue a través del Dr. Google, quizás no fue mi mejor movimiento, y no lo recomendaría. (Risas) Pero, aunque estaba preparada para los efectos secundarios físicos, lo que realmente me asustaba era eso llamado "quimio-cerebro". La quimio-cerebro se presenta en forma de pérdida de memoria, una incapacidad para concentrarse y una incapacidad para resolver problemas. Y si eso me ocurriera a mí, me preguntaba cómo haría mi trabajo de abogada. ¿Me obligarían a dejar el trabajo? ¿Y cómo podría tratar con mi gerente sobre los cambios necesarios para mi adaptación laboral cuando ni yo sabía cómo iba a afectarme? Tuve suerte por tener un gerente tan comprensivo que disfrutaba viendo que todo iba marchando bien, según avanzaba, en lugar de pedir un plan concreto por adelantado. Tuve la suerte de que a pesar de no haber oído nunca sobre este concepto de adaptaciones razonables, para él, era sentido común. Pero he aprendido que no es sentido común para todo el mundo. Cada persona que tome el tratamiento averiguará cómo le afecta y cuáles son sus limitaciones. Y aprenderán a adaptarse a ello. Yo tenía mis trucos y consejos que aprendí con el propio tratamiento, como, antes de ir a quimio, necesitan asegurarse de que están muy bien hidratados y que no están con frío porque ayuda a las enfermeras a encontrar las venas. Y asegúrense de que no comen ninguna de sus comidas favoritas, ni antes ni después de la quimio, porque la van a vomitar y no querrán verla otra vez. (Risas) Lo aprendí por las malas. Y luego estaban los trucos para organizar mi flujo de trabajo. Programaba la quimio el lunes por la mañana a primera hora. Sabía que desde el momento en que dejara la unidad de cuidado del cáncer, tenía cuatro horas antes de que la pantalla de niebla bajara y comenzara a sentir náuseas. Así que usaría ese tiempo para limpiar mi bandeja de entrada y hacer cualquier llamada urgente. Lo peor de la Indisposición habría desaparecido en aproximadamente 48 horas. Y luego volvería a conectarme al trabajo desde casa. Este tratamiento continuó y yo sabía qué esperar. Pude establecer expectativas razonables con mis socios comerciales sobre lo que podría hacer y los periodos de tiempo en los que podría hacerlo. Pero todavía recuerdo la vacilación en sus voces cuando venían a pedirme cosas, y pedirme que hiciera cosas en un tiempo determinado. Y créanme, estas eran personas que no tenían miedo de establecer una buena fecha límite. (Risas) Me daba la impresión de que no querían ponerme presión extra mientras estaba con el tratamiento. Y aunque apreciaba el sentimiento, de hecho, necesitaba esas fechas límites. Para mí, eso era algo dentro de mi control y algo que podía tener bajo control cuando había tantas cosas que no podía. Y mientras trabajaba desde casa, pensaba en cómo los empleadores deberían estar aplicando este concepto de las adaptaciones razonables en nuestra época actual, donde uno de cada dos hombres y mujeres australianos será diagnosticado con cáncer antes de los 85. Así que, mientras seguimos trabajando más y más hasta una edad avanzada, las posibilidades de tener una enfermedad grave mientras estamos activos laboralmente se van incrementado. Y con la tecnología que nos permite trabajar desde donde sea y cuando sea, las adaptaciones razonables ya no dependen de si puedes continuar o no haciéndolo físicamente dentro de la oficina física. Las adaptaciones razonables tampoco tratan de ofrecer un descanso más largo o una silla más cómoda para sentarse, aunque esas cosas también podrían estar bien. Por lo menos, necesitamos aplicar las políticas de flexibilidad y estrategias que hemos desarrollado para otros escenarios, como para las personas con responsabilidades familiares. Pero ¿cómo podemos asegurar que al menos se esté teniendo una conversación sobre cuales serían las adaptaciones razonables para ellos si la primera respuesta de un gerente es decir: "Oh no, no vuelva al trabajo hasta que esté mejor". Y una luz se me encendió. Debe ser obligatorio para los gerentes tener que sostener estas conversaciones con sus empleados. Y lecciones de personas como yo, que realmente se han beneficiado de trabajar con tratamiento, necesita ser compartido más ampliamente. Y pensé en lo que podría hacerse para guiar estas conversaciones, y luego una asombrosa colega mía, Camilla Gunn, desarrolló un manual para "Trabajar con Cáncer". Este manual proporciona un marco para aquellos diagnosticados, sus gerentes, sus cuidadores y sus compañeros de trabajo, para tratar el tema del cáncer y el apoyo disponible en el trabajo. Camilla y yo hemos estado en otras organizaciones para hablar sobre este manual y cómo puede ayudar a guiar esas conversaciones que de otra forma, sinceramente, serían muy difíciles. Y me complace decirles que el uso de este manual está aumentando. Así que, ¿cuál debería ser la primera respuesta de un gerente cuando alguien le dice que está enfermo y no sabe cómo va a afectar a su trabajo? Debe ser esta: "En la medida que Ud. sea capaz y quiera, nos encantaría hacer los cambios posibles para que continúe trabajando durante el tratamiento". Necesitamos empezar a comprometernos con los enfermos graves para mantenerlos activos en el trabajo, mejor que darles de lado paternalmente. Les he contado mi historia porque quiero que sepan los beneficios que obtuve al trabajar durante mi tratamiento. Y también quiero cambiar sus percepciones si piensan que alguien con tratamiento es solo alguien aburrido, frágil y alguien que vomita un montón. Y sí, era cierto algunas veces, o puede que muchas, pero también estaba decidida a esforzarme en el trabajo tanto como lo había hecho siempre. Y fui capaz de hacerlo porque mi empresa me dio la opción. Más importante aún, les estoy contando porque aunque es una elección aparentemente obvia que debe ser dada no es lo que siempre se ofrece o se promueve. Y debe serlo. Gracias a todos. (Aplausos)